http://www.tofs.org.uk/privacy-policy.aspx

Select a page to navigate to...
Contact Us
Questions about coronavirus and OA/TOF?
Click here to read our regularly updated advice.
Privacy Statement
Privacy StatementTOFS is committed to discharging it legal obligation to ensure the complete privacy of all personal data relating to members of the Charity, and others with whom the Charity interacts including advisors and supporters. This document tells you how and why we collect your data, how we secure, store, and use it, and your legal rights with respect to that data.Definitions and Interpretation The following definitions are used: In this privacy statementTracheo-Oesophageal Fistula Support (TOFS) (“we or us”) -  a charity registered with the charity commission number327735 and T.O.F.S. a company incorporated in England and Wales with registered number 02202260 whose registered office is at St Georges Centre, 91 Victoria Road, Netherfield, Nottingham, NG4 2NNData - collectively all information that you submit to TOFS, via the Website, or by any other means. This definition incorporates, where applicable, the definitions provided in the Data Protection Act 1998;Cookies - a small text file placed on your computer by this Website when you visit certain parts of the Website and/or when you use certain features of the Website. Details of the cookies used by this Website are set out in the clause below (Cookies);GDPR - the General Data Protection Regulation 2018 (<atarget="_blank" href="https://ico.org.uk/for-organisations/guide-to-the-general-data-protection-regulation-gdpr/">https://ico.org.uk);UK and EU Cookie Law - the Privacy and Electronic Communications (EC Directive) Regulations 2003 as amended by the Privacy and Electronic Communications (EC Directive) (Amendment) Regulations 2011 (https://ico.org.uk);User or you - any third party that accesses the Website or shares personal data with us and is not either (i) employed by TOFS and acting in the course of their employment or (ii) engaged as a consultant or otherwise providing services to TOFS and accessing the Website in connection with the provision of such services.Website(s) - the website that you are currently using (tofs.org.uk) and any sub-domains of these sites unless expressly excluded by their own terms and conditions.In this privacy policy, unless the context requires a different interpretation:the singular includes the plural and vice versa;references to sub-clauses, clauses, schedules or appendices are to sub-clauses, clauses, schedules or appendices of this privacy policy;a reference to a person includes firms, companies, government entities, trusts and partnerships;"including" is understood to mean "including without limitation";reference to any statutory provision includes any modification or amendment of it;the headings and sub-headings do not form part of this privacy policy.Scope of this Privacy StatementThis privacy policy applies to all legal obligations which TOFS must fulfil to ensure full compliance with GDPR This includes the actions of TOFS. and Users with respect to this Website. It does not extend to any websites that can be accessed from this Website including, but not limited to, any links we may provide to social media, or other websites. It also includes any data you may share with us by any other means.The Data We CollectThe only data which TOFS requires you to provide is that which is consistent with your membership of the Charity, namely your name, and contact information such as email addresses and telephone numbers.If you are a parent or guardian of a TOF child or you are a TOF adult you are invited to provide TOFS with personal medical data but there is no obligation for you to do so. You have the right to request a copy of all the data held by TOFS You also have the right to ask for some or all the data we hold to be amended or deleted.More about how TOFS collects, stores, and uses your dataRetention of DataData which is directly relevant to your membership of TOFS will be retained for as long as you remain a member of the Charity. Other data will be periodically deleted. If your membership ceases your personal data will be archived unless we receive legitimate instructions for it to be deletedOur Use of DataFor purposes of the Data Protection Act 1998, TOFS is the "data controller".We will retain any enquiry Data you submit only for so long as is necessary to process your enquiry.Unless we are obliged or permitted by law to do so, and subject to any third-party disclosures specifically set out in this policy (see Third Party Websites and Services), your Data will not be disclosed to third parties.All personal Data is stored securely in accordance with the principles of the Data Protection Act 1998. For more details on security see the clause below (Security).Third Party Websites and Servicesmay, from time to time, employ the services of other parties for dealing with certain processes necessary for the operation of the Website and member data base. The providers of such services have access to certain personal Data provided by Users of this Website, and members of the TOFS charity.Any Data used by such parties is used only to the extent required by them to perform the services that we request. Any use for other purposes is strictly prohibited. Furthermore, any Data that is processed by third parties will be processed within the terms of this privacy policy and in accordance with the Data Protection Act 1998.and GDPR2018If you require a full list of suppliers that may have access to your personal data then please contact the GDPR data controller at T.O.F.S. by email at datacontrol@tofs.org.uk.Links to Other WebsitesThis Website has links to the websitesWe have no control over such websites and are not responsible for the content of these websitesThis privacy policy does not extend to your use of such websitesYou are advised to read the privacy policy or statement of other websites prior to using them.Social MediaTOFS manages a Facebook group, but has no control over the over anything which is posted by anybody other than TOFS Trustees or employees. We will never post any personal data on the group other than that which you may have requested us to share, such as fund-raising events in which you may be involved.All matters relating to the privacy of information posted on the group site are governed entirely by the Google Privacy Policy.TOFS also has links to other social media sites. In all cases matters relating to the privacy of information are the responsibility of the site provider.SecurityData security is of the highest importance to TOFS and to protect your Data we have put in place suitable physical, electronic and managerial procedures to safeguard and secure Data. Most, but not all the data you share with us is collected via this Website as part of the membership application process.If password access is required for certain parts of the Website, you are responsible for keeping this password confidential.We endeavour to do our best to protect your personal Data, however, transmission of information over the internet is not entirely secure and is done at your own risk. We cannot guarantee the security of your Data transmitted through the Website.We ensure that any internal systems are password protected and that all reasonable steps have been taken to ensure the physical protection of personal data.CookiesWe use Google Analytics to help us improve our website, and the way you use it. This means that our website will remember you. It does so by placing cookies (small text files) on your device to keep track of usage data and provide information about how the site is being used such as the type of device being used to access our website, the number of times a person visits the website, the pages they access, and the time they remain on the site. However, it is important to understand the identity of the individuals is never made available to us. The information which TOFS receives is completely anonymous.  More about Cookies GeneralYou may not transfer any of your rights under this privacy policy to any other person. We may transfer our rights under this privacy policy where we reasonably believe your rights will not be affected.If any court or competent authority finds that any provision of this privacy policy (or part of any provision) is invalid, illegal or unenforceable, that provision or part-provision will, to the extent required, be deemed to be deleted, and the validity and enforceability of the other provisions of this privacy policy will not be affected.Unless otherwise agreed, no delay, act or omission by a party in exercising any right or remedy will be deemed a waiver of that, or any other, right or remedy.This Agreement will be governed by and interpreted according to the law of England and Wales. All disputes arising under the Agreement will be subject to the exclusive jurisdiction of the English and Welsh courts.You can at any time request that any, or all, personal data relating to yourself is deleted from our records.Changes to this Privacy StatementT.O.F.S. reserves the right to change this privacy statement as we may deem necessary from time to time, or as may be required by law. Any changes will be immediately posted on the Website and you are deemed to have accepted the terms of the privacy policy on your first use of the Website following the alterations.For more information you may contact the GDPR data controller at T.O.F.S. by email at datacontrol@tofs.org.uk.
Members' Area
Login
Reset Password
Become a Member of TOFS
Quick Links
Donate
Fundraising
Leaflets and Publications
Newsletter
News
Member Feedback
To all at TOFS, just a really big THANK YOU for being there. All I wanted was just for someone to listen and understand and you were there for me. Jo Wright, parent of a child born with OA/TOF
We wanted to thank you again for all the support you have given us over the phone and through your newsletter, website and online forum.  We have found TOFS an invaluable resource and spread the word wherever we can about the great work you do. Joanne and John Winspear, parents
The TOFS support group does exactly what it says on the tin!  It supports.  And that’s a very reassuring feeling - talking to people who have been there. You guys do a wonderful job. Rachel Simpson, parent
During my working life as a paediatric surgeon I learned as much, if not more about TOF from parents and from TOFS meetings as I did from learned journals. Leela Kapila, past Vice-President of the Royal College of Surgeons
When I read Chew, I’m encouraged by reading about the positive side of OA/TOF and the achievements of all the children and TOF adults. TOFS, the website, the Forum and Chew have all been a marvellous source of information and encouragement for us. Rachel and Mark Hayes, parents
Our bumpy ride has been so much easier with TOFS; just listening to other people’s experiences and knowing someone is there. Charlie and Lesley Cochrane, parents
Useful Links
Hospital Travel Cost
NHS scheme for help with travel costs for those who qualify
NHS 111
For when you need urgent medical advice and unable to contact your doctor
Adult TOF Facebook Group (endorsed by TOFS)
A (closed) Adult TOF Facebook Group, run by Adult TOF, Faye Baker, and endorsed by TOFS
Contact - for families with disabled children
UK charity which signposts parents to relevant support groups. CaF also provides resources on a range of issues (including benefits and rights) and offers the support of a Welfare Rights Officer. Directory for specific conditions, rare disorders and UK Family Support Groups.
View More
© Tracheo-Oesophageal Fistula Support
top of page | disclaimer | privacy statement | contact us
TOFS is a Registered Charity in England and Wales (327735) and a Private Company Limited By Guarantee without Share Capital, registered in England and Wales (2202260).Registered address: TOFS, St. George's Centre, 91 Victoria Road, Netherfield, Nottingham NG4 2NN.
Website by Altido
top of page | disclaimer | privacy policy | contact us
© Tracheo-Oesophageal Fistula Support
TOFS is a Registered Charity in England and Wales (327735) and a Private Company Limited By Guarantee without Share Capital, registered in England and Wales (2202260).Registered address: TOFS, St. George’s Centre, 91 Victoria Road, Netherfield, Nottingham NG4 2NN.
Website by Altido
Our team at TOFS is working tirelessly to bring you the latest advice regarding Coronavirus. The support and advice we provide are only possible thanks to kind donations from people like you. If you're able, please consider donating now.
Donate
Donate
